Lucas Ospina Centeno Systems and Telecommunications Engineer

- Manizales, Colombia
- **27/12/1985**
- lucasospinacenteno@gmail.com
- +573145428889
- in linkedin.com/in/lucas-ospina-centeno-ab170170/

Profile

I am a bilingual systems engineer with vast experience in testing processes. I am a responsible person, with a good attitude to carry out my activities, punctual, self-taught, always willing to learn, I distinguish myself by easily integrating into a work team.

Education

Systems and Telecommunications Engineering

Universidad de Manizales ♂

07/2012 - 01/2017 Manizales, Colombia

Systems Technologist

Universidad de Caldas ♂

07/2007 - 01/2011 Manizales, Colombia

Professional Experience

QA Release Manager 09/2023 - present Manizales, Colombia

PrimeWorks LLC ☑

- Team lead: Coordinate solutions with Dev team and QA team
- Azure DevOps Pipeline: Supervising Pull Requests (PRs) to ensure code quality and timely integration.
- Test Planning: Creating and managing test plans and test cases for comprehensive software evaluation.
- Developer Workflow: Overseeing and facilitating seamless collaboration among developers.
- Deployment: Managing code deployment across various environments, including production.

Used Methodologies: SCRUM methodology

Used technology: Agile Platforms

Used Tools:

Azure DevOps

Screen recorders

Git (Azure DevOps pipeline visual interface)

Browserstack

QA Engineer Perficient

• Design and develop comprehensive test plans and scenarios.

04/2022 - 07/2023 Manizales, Colombia

- Prepare systems for implementation by testing modifications.
- Create testing plans covering software scenarios, regression, negative, and usability testing.
- Document and report software defects using a bug tracking system.
- Provide developers with feedback and recommendations on software usability and functionality.

Used Methodologies: SCRUM methodology

Used technology: Agile Platforms

Used Tools: Atlassian Jira Screen recorders Postman **Jenkins**

GitHub

Windows Remote Desktop (Servers)

Tester - Freelance 01/2022 - 02/2022 Hexacta Manizales, Colombia

- Create and execute detailed test plans, scenarios, and procedures.
- Test system modifications to ensure readiness for implementation.
- Develop comprehensive testing plans, including software scenarios, regression, negative testing, and retests for errors or bugs.
- Document and report software defects using a bug tracking system.
- Offer feedback and recommendations to developers on software usability and functionality.

Used Methodologies: SCRUM methodology

Used technology: Agile Platforms

Used tools:

- Azure DevOps
- Screen recorders

QA Engineer - Freelance

Ontop Holdings Inc.

- Design and develop comprehensive test plans and scenarios.
- Prepare systems for implementation by testing modifications.
- Create testing plans covering software scenarios, regression, negative, and usability testing.
- Document and report software defects using a bug tracking system.
- Provide developers with feedback and recommendations on software usability and functionality.

Used Methodologies: SCRUM methodology

Used tools:

- Atlassian Jira
- Screen recorders
- BrowserStack

QA Analyst 08/2020 - 11/2021 Yuxi Global S.A.S. ☑ Manizales, Colombia

• Create and execute detailed test plans, scenarios, and procedures.

11/2021 - 12/2021 Manizales, Colombia

- Test system modifications to ensure readiness for implementation.
- Develop comprehensive testing plans, including software scenarios, regression, negative testing, and retests for errors or bugs.
- Document and report software defects using a bug tracking system.
- Offer feedback and recommendations to developers on software usability and functionality.

Used Methodologies: SCRUM methodology **Used technology:** iOS devices - Agile Platforms

Used tools:Atlassian Jira

- Azure DevOps
- Screen recorders
- TestRail
- BrowserStack

Quality Assurance Engineer

Heinsohn Business Technology ♂

• Design and develop comprehensive test plans and scenarios.

- Prepare systems for implementation by testing modifications.
- Create testing plans covering software scenarios, regression, negative, and usability testing.
- Document and report software defects using a bug tracking system.
- Provide developers with feedback and recommendations on software usability and functionality.

Used Methodologies: SCRUM methodology

Used technology: iOS / Android mobile devices - Agile Platforms

Used tools:

- · Atlassian Jira
- Jama Software
- Screen recorders
- Postman

SAP Success Factors Technician

ARAGO Consulting S.A.S. □

• Answer user inquiries regarding computer software or hardware operation to resolve problems.

- Modify and customize commercial programs for internal needs.
- Maintain records of daily data communication transactions, problems and remedial actions taken, or installation activities.
- Provide support for the Employee Central, Performance and General modules of SAP Success Factors.

Used technology: XML, JSON, ODATA, PHP

Used tools:

- SAP Success Factors Manager
- Visual Studio Code
- Open Office
- Zendesk

09/2019 – 07/2020 Manizales, Colombia

08/2017 – 08/2019 Manizales, Colombia

Testing Engineer

Dev Penguin S.A.S. ☑

07/2016 – 06/2017 Manizales, Colombia

- Design test plans, scenarios, or procedures.
- Test system modifications to prepare for implementation.
- Develop testing plans that address areas such as software scenarios, regression testing, negative testing, error or bug retests, or usability.
- Document software defects, using a bug tracking system, and report defects to software developers.
- Provide feedback and recommendations to developers on software usability and functionality.
- Unit, manual and stress tests in web applications, test design, defect reports.

Used Methodologies: Unit tests, white box, gray box

Used technology: Quality testing software

Used tools:

- Webserver Stress Tool Paessler
- Oracle VirtualBox
- Trello
- Adobe Captivate
- SOAPUI
- JSON

Organizations

Caldas NGO Federation 🗗

Web Master

07/2016 – 01/2017 Manizales, Colombia

Implement federation image and various web services. Management of CRM / CMS software.

Methodologies Used: SCRUM

Technologies Used: Front-end web development, Databases

Used tools:

- Cpanel
- SQL
- Wordpress
- Dollibar
- Softaculous
- XAMPP
- FileZilla
- Visual Studio Code
- SQL

Certificates

- Tester Fundación Carlos Slim
 ☑
- Certificate of Completion: HTML Fundamentals SoloLearn ☑
- EF SET English Certificate (69/100 C1 Advanced) ☑
- Certificate of Completion: CSS Fundamentals SoloLearn ☑
- Certificate of Completion: Java Tutorial - SoloLearn ☑
- Certificate of Completion: PHP Course SoloLearn ☑

Languages

English • • • • Spanish

EF SET English Certificate (69/100 C1 Advanced)

Native Language

References

Julián Andrés Gallego Molano, *Data Engineer*, PWL Capital jgallego_2001@yahoo.com, +16725154008

David Ricardo Martínez Dallos, *Executive Director*, Caldas NGO Federation davidrmartinezd@gmail.com, +573015866171

Authorization

I, Lucas Ospina Centeno, with identification number CC 75107843 and date of birth 27/12/1985, agree to participate in the vacancy of Release Engineer Lead and authorize the use of my resume and the information to continue with the selection process for the said vacancy.

Lucas Ospina Centeno

Manizales